L’Aerophile Collection
Science, Technology, & Business Division, Library of Congress
- Types of Aircraft (Box 75-117)
  - United States #2 D-NO. (Box 96)
    - U.S Navy Hellcat Fighter. (Envelope 14)
    - Hughes Flying Boat (Hercules). (Envelope 15)
    - Jet & Propeller Navy Fighter. (Envelope 16)
    - (Glen) Martin. (Envelope 17)
    - Martin B26. (Envelope 18)
    - Martin 202. (Envelope 19)
    - Martin 303. (Envelope 20)
    - Martin Mariner. (Envelope 21)
    - Martin “Mars” Flying Boat. (Envelope 22)
    - Martin T.T. (Envelope 23)
    - Martin XP4M-1 & Mauler. (Envelope 24)
    - Military Transport Planes. (Envelope 25)
    - Miscellaneous Aviation. (Envelope 26)
    - Navion. (Envelope 27)
    - North American P51. (Envelope 28)
    - North American Aviation XAJ-1. (Envelope 29)
    - North American Aviation XAJ-1. (Envelope 30)
    - Northrop. (Envelope 31)
    - Northrop Black Widow P-61. (Envelope 32)
  - United States #3 and Canada P-Z. (Box 97)
    - P-82 Twin Mustang. (Envelope 1)
    - Piper Super Cruiser. (Envelope 2)
    - Republic P47. (Envelope 3)
    - Republic P84. (Envelope 4)
    - Republic Rainbow. (Envelope 5)
    - Republic Seabee. (Envelope 6)
    - Ryan. (Envelope 7)
    - Ryan Fireball. (Envelope 8)
    - S.F.A.N. (Envelope 9)
    - Sandringham. (Envelope 10)
    - The Short Seaford Flying Boat. (Envelope 11)
    - Sikorsky. (Envelope 12)
    - Skyranger. (Envelope 13)
    - The Skystreak. (Envelope 14)
    - Stearman. (Envelope 15)
    - U.S. Superbomber. (Envelope 16)
    - Trimmer. (Envelope 17)
    - Vega Airplane. (Envelope 18)
    - Vought. (Envelope 19)
    - Vickers Armstrong. (Envelope 20)
    - Wedell-Williams Type 44. (Envelope 21)
    - Weick. (Envelope 22)
    - Photographs: Wright Brothers’ Plane. (Envelope 23)
    - Wright C. Airplane. (Envelope 24)
    - Wright Airplane. (Envelope 25)
    - (L’Avion Ecole) X5M2-J1-7. (Envelope 26)
    - Canadian Car & Foundry. (Envelope 27)
    - De Havilland “Chipmunk.” (Envelope 28)
    - Miscellaneous Canadian Aircrafts. (Envelope 29)
  - United States, Boeing. (Box 98)
    - Boeing Passenger Aircrafts. (Envelope 1)
    - The Boeing Stratocruiser. (Envelope 2)
    - Boeing Kaydet. (Envelope 3)
    - Boeing Bombers. (Envelope 4)
    - Boeing B-29. (Envelope 5)
    - Boeing Stratocruiser. (Envelope 6)
    - Boeing Stratoliner. (Envelope 7)
    - Boeing 47 Transport. (Envelope 8)
    - Boeing YC97. (Envelope 9)
  - United States Consolidated Vultee. (Box 99)
    - Consolidated Aircraft Corporation. (Envelope 1)
    - Consolidated Vultee. (Envelope 2)
    - Consolidated Vultee “Catalina.” (Envelope 3)
    - Consolidated Vultee Corporation B32. (Envelope 4)
    - Consolidated Vultee L13. (Envelope 5)
    - Consolidated Vultee XA41. (Envelope 6)
    - Consolidated Vultee XB36. (Envelope 7)
    - Consolidated Vultee XB46. (Envelope 8)
    - Curtiss-Wright XBT2C & Consolidated Vultee. (Envelope 9)
    - Consolidated Vultee Corporation Privateer. (Envelope 10)
    - Vultee Aircraft. (Envelope 11)
  - United States, Fairchild. (Box 100)
    - Fairchild Model 24 (1937). (Envelope 1)
    - Fairchild. (Envelope 2)
    - Fairchild F24. (Envelope 3)
    - Fairchild XN21. (Envelope 4)
  - United States, Lockheed. (Box 101)
    - Lockheed P38. (Envelope 1)
    - Lockheed Shooting Star. (Envelope 2)
    - Lockheed. (Envelope 3)
    - Lockheed Constellation. (Envelope 4)
    - Lockheed 1930s. (Envelope 5)
  - Unidentified countries. (Box 102)
    - Burnelli. (Envelope 1)
    - Sanchez Besa (1912). (Envelope 2)
    - Sanchis. (Envelope 3)
    - Savary (Reims). (Envelope 4)
    - Paul Schmitt (Chartres). (Envelope 5)
    - Theodoresco. (Envelope 6)
    - Vuia. (Envelope 7)
    - Passenger Aircrafts. (Envelope 8)
    - Experimental Aircraft. (Envelope 9)
  - Miscellaneous Countries, Austria-Germany. (Box 103)
    - Austria Miscellaneous. (Envelope 1)
    - Balkan Aviation. (Envelope 2)
    - J. Stampe & M. Vertongen (Belgium). (Envelope 3)
    - Miscellaneous Aircrafts (Belgium). (Envelope 4)
    - Tipsy (Belgium). (Envelope 5)
    - Tipsy (Belgium) “Bellair.” (Envelope 6)
    - Brazil “Modele Reduits.” (Envelope 7)
    - Santos Dumont (Brazil). (Envelope 8)
    - Auster Aircraft (British Isles). (Envelope 9)
    - Egypt Miscellaneous Aircraft. (Envelope 10)
    - Franco-British Aviation. (Envelope 11)
    - Germany Miscellaneous Aviation. (Envelope 12)
    - Italy Stupa. (Envelope 13)
    - Iran Aviation. (Envelope 14)
    - Japan Aviation. (Envelope 15)
  - Miscellaneous Countries, Holland-Romania. (Box 104)
    - Fokker (Holland). (Envelope 1)
    - Farner Flugzeugloau (Holland). (Envelope 2)
    - Koolhoven (Holland). (Envelope 3)
    - N.V. Koninklijke Maatschappij “deschelde” (Holland). (Envelope 4)
    - Pander (Holland). (Envelope 5)
    - P.Z.L. (Poland). (Envelope 6)
    - P.Z.L. (Poland). (Envelope 7)
    - RWD (Poland). (Envelope 8)
    - ICAR (Romania). (Envelope 9)
    - Miscellaneous Aviation Romania. (Envelope 10)
  - Russia-Yugoslavia. (Box 105)
    - Helicopters (Russia). (Envelope 1)
    - Miscellaneous Sweden. (Envelope 2)
    - Miscellaneous Aviation Switzerland. (Envelope 3)
    - Miscellaneous Aviation Russia. (Envelope 4)
    - Rogojarsky S.A. (Yugoslavia). (Envelope 5)
    - Nasa Krila (Yugoslavia). (Envelope 6)
    - S.I.M. (Yugoslavia). (Envelope 7)
  - Misc. Aircraft and parts. (Box 106)
    - Australian Aircrafts. (Envelope 1)
    - England: Photographs of Aircrafts, 1930-1960. (Envelope 2)
    - England: Photographs of Aircrafts. (Envelope 3)
    - England: Photographs of Non-Aircraft. (Envelope 4)
    - France: Photographs, 1940-1960. (Envelope 5)
    - France: Photographs WWII. (Envelope 6)
    - Germany: Small Aircraft Photographs. (Envelope 7)
    - United States: Photographs, 1910-1930. (Envelope 8)
    - United States: Photographs. (Envelope 9)
    - United States: Aircraft Photographs. (Envelope 10)
    - Photographs: Aircrafts of Various Countries. (Envelope 11)
    - Belgium. (Envelope 12)
    - Germany. (Envelope 13)
    - Poland. (Envelope 14)
    - Morocco. (Envelope 15)
    - Romania. (Envelope 16)
    - Sweden. (Envelope 17)
    - Switzerland. (Envelope 18)
  - Miscellaneous Aircraft and Non-Aircraft. (Box 106A)
    - Negatives: Unknown Aircraft. (Envelope 1)
      - Two negatives of unknown aircraft. (Item 1)
    - Miscellaneous German Aircraft. (Envelope 2)
    - Miscellaneous Aircraft, 1910-1920. (Envelope 3)
    - Miscellaneous Aircraft, 1920-1940. (Envelope 4)
    - Germany: Non-Aircraft. (Envelope 5)
    - Miscellaneous Aircraft Photographs. (Envelope 6)
    - Miscellaneous Aircraft Photographs #2 (Before 1914). (Envelope 7)
    - Miscellaneous Aircraft Photographs #3. (Envelope 8)
    - Non-Aircraft Photographs. (Envelope 9)
    - Non-Aircraft Photographs #2 (Before 1914). (Envelope 10)
    - Non-Aircraft Photographs #3 (Envelope 11)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs. (Envelope 12)
    - Miscellaneous Aircraft, 1900-1940. (Envelope 13)
    - Non-Aircraft Photographs. (Envelope 14)
  - Balloons, France, pre-WWI. (Box 107)
    - Balloons-Monsieur Charles Robert (Photographs of Engravings). (Envelope 1)
      - Photograph of an engraving depicting an eighteenth-century balloon, (2 copies). (Item 1)
      - Two photographs of engravings depicting the balloon flight of “MM. Charles et Robert” in the garden of Thuilleries, December 1, 1783. (Item 2)
    - Ballooning Before WWI. (Envelope 2)
      - Photograph of Alberto Santos-Dumant and others. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of “Deux Américains” (two Americans) in the balloon “St. Louis.” (Item 2)
      - Photograph of the balloon “Belgique”, July 1905. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of a balloon at L’Aero Club 1905. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of Zurich with balloons added. (Item 5)
      - Photograph of Surcouf and Henri Kapferer. (Item 6)
      - Early photograph of a balloon in the shape of “Bibendum” (the Michelin Man). (Item 7)
      - Two photographs of Mme. Surcouf departing in a balloon. (Item 8)
      - Photograph of a Hélice (Propeller) of Jacque Faure. (Item 9)
      - Photograph before a competition of “Hydroaeroplanes” in St. Malo, France. (Item 10)
      - Thirty-three unidentified photographs of balloons and pilots. (Item 11)
    - Balloons-Montgolfiere Brothers. (Envelope 3)
      - Photograph of an eighteenth-century print depicting the Montgolfiere Brothers in 1784. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of an eighteenth-century engraving depicting the Marquis d’Arlandes, 1783. (Item 2)
      - Eight photographs of Montgolfiere balloons in various stages of inflation. (Item 3)
    - Balloon Photographs. (Envelope 4)
      - Two photographs mounted on cardboard of Henri Deutsch de la Meurthe, Henri Farman, Charles Voisin and Gabriel Voisin (1908). (Item 1)
      - Cartoon print depicting “Les Ballonistes du ‘Cambronne’ 4 Novembre 1906.” (Item 2)
      - Photograph of an engraving depicting the passage of the S.M Louis, May 5, 1814. (Item 3)
      - Seven unidentified photographs of balloons and balloonists. (Item 4)
    - Mallet Balloons. (Envelope 5)
      - Two photograph of “Maurice Mallet Construction d’Aérostats” interior and exterior. (Item 1)
    - Spherical Balloons (France). (Envelope 6)
      - Photograph of a balloon bearing the flag of the Ottoman Empire, 1909. (Item 1)
      - Photograph taken from a balloon over Istanbul [Constantinople], Turkey (facing south, Hagia Sophia in distance). (Item 2)
      - Two photographs of the “Concours de Bully.” (Item 3)
      - Photograph of two balloons on ships. (Item 4)
      - Three mounted photographs portraying a balloon (Andre Schelcher?) lifting off and landing (2 copies). (Item 5)
      - Unidentified photograph “Zodiac.” (Item 6)
    - Engravings of Balloons (France), 1780s. (Envelope 7)
      - “Première Montgolfière portent MM. Pilâtre de Rozier et le marquis d’Alandes.” (Item 1)
      - “Le Flesselles.” (Item 2)
      - Two engravings: “Arrivée de MM. Charles et Robert dans la prairie de Nesle” and “Deuxième voyage aérien — MM. Charles et Robert (1er décembre 1783).” (Item 3)
      - Two engravings: “Mort de Pilâtre et de Romain” and “Aéro-Montgolfière de Pilâtre de Rozier (16 juin 1785).” (Item 4)
      - Two engravings: “Gonglement du premier ballon de MM. Charles et Robert. Rue Notre-Dame-des-Victoires” and “Manière de gonfler un ballon avec de l’hydrogène obtenu par la decomposition de l’eau.” (Item 5)
      - “Grande Montgolfière de Versailles enlerant un mouton, un coq et un canard.” (Item 6)
      - “Bateau Volant de Lana.” (Item 7)
      - “Ascension de Testu-Brissy (17 juin 1786).” (Item 8)
      - “Montgolfière sans voyageurs.” (Item 9)
      - “Quatrième royage aèrien — Don Paul Andreani.” (Item 10)
    - Sounding Balloons. (Envelope 8)
      - Photograph of a mercurial barometer, 1895. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of a graph that depicts the barometric pressure and temperature over the course of a balloon voyage, 1896. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of a map charting a balloon voyage with a corresponding chart of the barometric pressure, 1895. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of a graph of the altitude, temperature and pressure over the course of a balloon voyage, 1893. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of a “Thermographe” used on a balloon voyage, 1893. (Item 5)
      - “Map of Europe With the Radius Distance Travelled by the Touring Club”, 1896. (Item 6)
      - Graphs describing the barometric pressure and temperature for the ascension of the balloon “le Touring Club”, 1896. (Item 7)
      - Twenty-five unidentified photographs of balloons, balloon hangars, balloon equipment, measuring devices and barometric graphs. (Item 8)
    - “Concours de Ballons” (Balloon Contests). (Envelope 9)
      - Stereoview of a balloon in a hangar. (Item 1)
      - Photograph “Le Ballon Jules Verne. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of the air festival “Stella,”, 1914. (Item 3)
      - Clipping depicting the balloon “l’Hirondelle” of the “l’Aéro-Club de France.” (Item 4)
      - Photograph from the grand prix of the l’Aéro-Club. (Item 5)
      - Photograph of the balloon “l’Hirondelle”, 1905. (Item 6)
      - Photograph of the balloon “Belle Hélene.” (Item 7)
      - Photograph of the French War Minister and Minister to England. (Item 8)
      - Photograph of G. Besançon departing in a balloon, 1903. (Item 9)
      - Photograph of a man observing an advertisement for an aviation exposition, 1909. (Item 10)
      - Photograph of the balloon “La Bouraine” departing. (Item 11)
      - Approximately eighty-five photographs of balloon competitions, expositions, hangars and pilots. (Item 12)
    - Balloons: Malécot. (Envelope 10)
      - Thirteen photographs of the dirigible “Malécot” 1907-1908. (Item 1)
    - “Balloons de la Vaux.” (Envelope 11)
      - Approximately fifty photographs pertaining to Comte de la Vaulx’s 1901 attempt to cross the Mediterranean by balloon. The photographs depict the construction of Vaulx’s hangar on the coast of Toulon, France. The photographs also depict the balloon in various stages of inflation and Vaulx’s equipment. (Item 1)
    - International Balloon Contests. (Envelope 12)
      - Thirty-two photographs of international balloon contests. (Item 1)
  - Balloons, Miscellaneous #1. (Box 108)
    - Aumont Thieville balloon festival (“Prix Aumant Thieville des Spheriques”). (Envelope 1)
      - Seven photographs of the Aumont Thieville balloon festival. (Item 1)
    - Women’s Ballon Rally (A.C.F.). (Envelope 2)
      - Twenty-four photographs of the Women’s Balloon Rally. The photographs depict balloons, airplanes, aerial views and pilots. (Item 1)
    - Stratospheric Ascensions Balloons. (Envelope 3)
      - Three photographs of Major William Kepner, leader of National Geographic Society Army Air Corps Stratospheric Flight, standing in front of the Stratospheric Balloon. Rapid City, South Dakota, 1934. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of Willey Post after achieving an altitude of 14,630 Meters, 1934. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of Alice Gibson wearing parachute gear after completing a record parachute drop, 1935. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of Major William Kepner and Captain Albert W. Stevens, Army Air Corps Stratospheric Flight, 1934. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of scholars from Massachusetts Institute of Technology discussing the implications of Stratospheric Flight. Dr. Carl G. Rossby, Dr. J. Bjerkness and Dr. Hurd C. Willet are pictured, 1934. (Item 5)
      - Photograph depicting a stratospheric balloon landing, 1935. (Item 6)
      - Photograph of Jean Piccard, Jeanette Ridlon Piccard and Edward J. Hill ascending in a balloon. (Item 7)
      - Photograph of Jean Piccard and Max Cosyns in a laboratory at the University of Brussells, 1934. (Item 8)
      - Photograph of a pilot training on an exercise bike in a decompression room, 1935. (Item 9)
      - Photograph of Jean Piccard and William R. Enyart experimenting with a “Barographe”, 1934. (Item 10)
      - Ariel view of a stratospheric balloon landing. (Item 11)
      - Photograph of the National Geographic Society camp in Black Hills, North Dakota, 1935. (Item 12)
      - Photograph of Captain Orville Anderson and Captain R.P. Williams departing by balloon for the stratosphere. (Item 13)
      - Eight photographs pertaining to the Army Air Corps Stratospheric Flight. (Item 14)
    - U.S. Balloon. (Envelope 4)
      - Photograph of Alberto Santos-Dumont descending to his balloon-shed, 1901. (Item 1)
    - “Hydrolithe” (Balloons). (Envelope 5)
      - Three photographs of an inflating balloon outside the ”Aéro-Club De France.” (Item 1)
      - Photograph of the interior of a balloon hangar? (Item 2)
    - “Stratospheric” Balloons. (Envelope 6)
      - Max Cosyns departing for the stratosphere. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of a model for a stratospheric balloon. (Item 2)
      - Two photographs pertaining to the stratospheric balloon. (Item 3)
    - Balloons and Kite Balloons. (Envelope 7)
      - Photograph of the balloon “Une Saucisse Motorisee,” The Motorized Sausage, 1934. (Item 1)
      - Seven photographs of a French military observation balloon (kite balloon). (Item 2)
      - Three dirigible photographs. (Item 3)
    - Balloon Air Festival (Stella). (Envelope 8)
      - Two photographs of Madame Boyer. (Item 1)
      - Photograph: Stella medal. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of a balloon piloted by Mme. Goldschmidt. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of Henri Kapferer, Mme. Airault and Mme. Cloyel in a balloon. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of Henri Kapferer in a balloon. (Item 5)
      - Five photographs of women aviators at “Stella” 1912 presenting a flag “Aeronautique Militaire: Fleurus Extreme-Orient Maroc.” Henri Deutsch de la Meurthe stands in the foreground. (Item 6)
      - Photograph of the balloon ”La Gascogne” departing (2 copies). (Item 7)
      - Photograph of the balloon “La Bouraine” departing; piloted by Mme. Tissot. (Item 8)
      - Group photograph of women aviators at Stella. (Item 9)
      - Mme. Tissot departing at Stella. (Item 10)
      - Madame Surcouf departing at Stella. (Item 11)
      - Mme. Goldschmidt departing from Stella, 1911. (Item 12)
      - Detail photograph of the 1912 Stella Flag. (Item 13)
      - Group photograph in Mme. Surcouf’s home. Mme Surcouf and Mme Airault are pictured among others. (Item 14)
      - Approximately forty photographs of balloons and aviators at Stella. (Item 15)
    - Balloon Aviation (Russia). (Envelope 9)
      - Approximately twenty pre-WWI photographs of Russian kite balloons, dirigibles, a camp for balloon experiments and a hydrogen pump. (Item 1)
    - Balloons (National Atomic Energy Association). (Envelope 10)
      - Three photographs from the “Grand Prix Deutsch” 1911. (Item 1)
      - Fourteen photographs of the balloon “AXA Remplace Le Beurre Fin.” (Item 2)
      - l’Aérophile flyer describing advertising rates. (Item 3)
      - Approximately forty photographs of balloon events at the Aero-Club of France. (Item 4)
  - Balloons, Miscellaneous #2. (Box 109)
    - Balloons: Santos Dumont. (Envelope 1)
      - Approximately fifty photographs of Alberto Santos-Dumant, his hangar and dirigibles 9, 10, 14 and 16. (Item 1)
    - Balloons before 1870 (Leonard & de Vinci). (Envelope 2)
      - Six photographs of prints depicting early-aviation designs. The photographs include Leonardo Da Vinci’s sketches and early designs for helicopters and gliders. (Item 1)
    - Canada Balloons. (Envelope 3)
      - Five photographs mounted on cardboard depicting a voyage from Montreal. (Item 1)
    - Germany Balloons. (Envelope 4)
      - Short handwritten biographies of five aviators. (Item 1)
      - Handwritten biography and two letters of Richard (Altmann?), 1900. (Item 2)
      - Four photographs and one newspaper clipping of the dirigibles “Shütte-Lanz” I and II. (Item 3)
      - Clipping depicting a dirigible hangar in Leipzig. (Item 4)
      - Three postcards depicting a German dirigible. (Item 5)
      - Three clippings and photographs of the dirigible “Siemens Schukert.” (Item 6)
      - Three clippings of models for the Shütte-Lanz. (Item 7)
      - Three photographs and clippings of the dirigible “Schwaben.” (Item 8)
      - Photograph and clipping of the dirigible “Suchard.” (Item 9)
      - Clipping of the dirigible “Veeh I.” (Item 10)
      - Five photographs of Richard Clouth and his dirigible. (Item 11)
      - Article: “Das Haus Des Luftschiffes.” (Item 12)
      - Approximately twenty photographs, articles, clippings and postcards of zeppelins, dirigibles and balloons. (Item 13)
    - Italy Balloons. (Envelope 5)
      - Two articles from “La Navigazione Aerea” on Enrico Forlanini. (Item 1)
      - Approximately thirty photographs of Italian dirigibles and balloons. (Item 2)
    - England Balloons. (Envelope 6)
      - Four photographs of man-powered airships including the “Sky Cycle” and “Gas Kite.” The airships used screw sails to propel the balloons. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of the “Electric Aerial Torpedo,” an airship exhibited at the St. Louis Exposition in 1900 and employed an electric motor. (Item 2)
      - Two photographic postcards of the “Nulli Secundus: The New British Air War Balloon”, 1907. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of the military-airship “Delta.” (Item 4)
      - Matted print of the “proposed Aerial Cruiser.” The hydrogen balloon was designed for American coastal defense and the design proposed using dynamite to destroy “hostile fleet[s]”, 1937. (Item 5)
      - Two photographs of balloon tests at Forty Meyer, Washington D.C., 1908. (Item 6)
      - Approximately twenty-five photographs, postcards and clippings of English military balloons and dirigibles. (Item 7)
    - Spain Balloons. (Envelope 7)
      - Three photographs of Federico Capone’s “Aérogyroplane.” (Item 1)
      - Twelve photographs of the dirigible “Astra,” including pictures from its first flight and accident. (Item 2)
      - Two photographs of Alberto Santos-Dumant’s dirigible. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of soldiers preparing to inflate a military balloon. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of the military-dirigible “España.” (Item 5)
      - Photograph of the balloon “Astra-Torres No. 1.” (Item 6)
      - Three photographs of soldiers experimenting with balloons near Madrid. (Item 7)
      - Photograph of the balloon “Fernandez Duro” 1907. (Item 8)
      - Approximately fifteen unidentified photographs of balloons and dirigibles. (Item 9)
    - Sweden Balloons. (Envelope 8)
      - Two photographs of Swedish balloons, 1903. (Item 1)
    - Balloons Equipment. (Envelope 9)
      - Diagram that describes balloon equipment. (Item 1)
  - Dirigibles #1 Countries A-H. (Box 110)
    - “Astra” Dirigibles. (Envelope 1)
      - Eight photographs of the dirigible “Éclaireur Conté”, 1912. (Item 1)
      - Two photographs of the dirigible “Astra” on its maiden voyage to Russia, 1913. (Item 2)
      - Thirteen unidentified photographs of “Astra” dirigibles with views of the Astra hangar. (Item 3)
      - Three photographs of the dirigible “Ville de Pau.” (Item 4)
      - Seventeen photographs of the dirigible “Ville de Nancy.” (Item 5)
      - Thirty-eight photographs of the dirigible “Ville De Paris,” including a photograph of Surcouf and Kapferer, 1906. (Item 6)
      - Fourteen photographs and a diagram of the dirigible “Adjudant Réau.” (Item 7)
      - Ten photographs of the dirigible “Ville de Bruxelles”, 1910. (Item 8)
    - Clement Bayard #1. (Envelope 2)
      - One hundred and four photographs and postcards of Clement Bayard’s dirigibles (Clement Bayard I-VII) and equipment with pictures a hangar in various stages of completion, Bastille day celebrations, a dirigible flying over La Église de la Madeleine (Madeleine Church, Paris), a dirigible accident, the “Grand Palais” of the Salon de l’Aéronautique (Paris Air Show, held in the same building as the Paris Exhibition of 1900)and pictures of Henri Kapferer, Sabatier, Baudry, Clément and Surcouf. (Item 1)
      - Le “Ville de Bordeaux,” five photographs of Bayard’s exhibit at the first Paris Air Show “Salon de l’Aéronautique” held in the Grand Palais in Paris (the same building as the Paris Exhibition of 1900). (Item 2)
      - Seven photographs of the dirigible “Adjudant Vincenot.” (Item 3)
      - Fourteen photographs of the dirigible “Colonel Renard.” (Item 4)
      - Four photographs of the dirigible “Bayard-Clement II.” (Item 5)
    - Clement Bayard #2. (Envelope 3)
      - Twenty-three photographs of Bayard’s dirigibles. (Item 1)
    - Bradsky Dirigibles. (Envelope 4)
      - Seven photographs of Bradsky and his dirigibles. (Item 1)
    - Godard Dirigibles & Balloons. (Envelope 5)
      - An envelope containing eleven photographs of the dirigible “Belgique.” (Item 1)
      - Photograph of a dirigible engine burner testing inside a dirigible hangar. (Item 2)